<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To all the people who meet in the steeple-houses in England and elsewhere</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 19KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40294</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15690498</idno>
  <idno type="VID">104397</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240886545</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1951</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36424</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">15690498</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40294)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104397)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1593:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To all the people who meet in the steeple-houses in England and elsewhere</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Simmons ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1657.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed: G.F.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained, with print show-through and loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Apocalyptic literature.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  Doctrines.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="tract">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:104397:1"/>
            <head>To all the PEOPLE Who meet in the STEEPLE-HOUSES IN <hi>ENGLAND,</hi> And elsewhere.</head>
            <p>THE mighty day of the Lord is coming, therof <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Christ is crying, and God that made the world, dwelleth not in temples made with hands, neither is he worshipped in the Steeplehouses which <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e made with mens hands, and you think to worship him there; but God is a Spirit, and must be worshipped in spirit and in truth; and he hath given to every one a measure of his spirit to profit withall; in the spirit is God wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shipped, the Father of spirits; for there was a time that there was an outward temple which God com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded; but for witnessing against it, and witnessing the Scripture, <hi>Stephen</hi> was stoned to death, <hi>Acts</hi> 7.
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:104397:2"/>And <hi>Paul</hi> for witnessing against it, and saying, <hi>God that made the world doth not dwell in Temples made with hands,</hi> was persecuted. God is a spirit, &amp; must be worshipped in spirit, in that spirit that gave forth the Letter; which spirit was in them that gave it forth. So all you that have the letter in <hi>England</hi> which was given forth by that spirit, and calls a steeplehouse a Church, and do not worship God in spirit, therefore to you all this is sent a Message from the Lord Jesus Christ in <hi>England,</hi> or elsewhere, into all the steeple-houses, or elsewhere to be read; for God is a spirit, and they that worship him must worship him in spirit and in truth; and such were drove out of the synagogues, drove out of the Idols temple, and drove together, and so an Epistle was written to them: And God is the same, he is a spirit, and his spirit is drawing from all steeplehouses now where it is ruling, the spirit that gave forth the Scriptures, in which spirit have all the saints unity, which spirit draws up to God; but ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving not the spirit, but the letter, as the world have, there are the sects and all the opinions; one saith there is Christ, and another saith, Lo there is Christ; one saith this is the meaning, and another saith this is the meaning; and these are them that witnesse <hi>Oxford</hi> and <hi>Cambridge</hi> the two Mothers of Divinity, which now the Lords hand is against, and his sword is drawn against; and the spirit draws from all stee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plehouses and teachers which have the Law to guard them, that none must speak but themselves, if they do, either to the stocks with them, or knock them down, or imprison them, or persecute them with hands or tongues, or limit them with their law which the beast hath made; these are the cage of unclean birds which
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:104397:2"/>the spirit prophesied of in the <hi>Revelations,</hi> and their mother of harlots, who are harlotted from the spirit, the true worship of the living God; but now is the day of the Lord coming that all things shall be made manifest, and discovered and seen; all you which are without the life which gave forth the Scriptures, you have the letter onely which proceeds from the life, and your Teachers made at <hi>Oxford</hi> &amp; <hi>Cambridge,</hi> which are called of men Masters, which the woe is upon; and they are such as bear rule by their means, which <hi>Jeremiah</hi> cryed against which was in the life; so the spirits of the prophets are over yours and your Teachers, some of them build you up, and some of them throw you down, and there they are Babylon; and some say this is the way; and some say that is the way; and some say lo here is Christ, and some say lo there is Christ, and there they are such as Christ bids beware of; and they tell people of a mediate call, and mediate means, and that is natural, and the natural man knows not the things of God; so they are in their witchcraft and whoredom, from the life of God, &amp; the Prophets of Christ cryed wo against such as them, and their church is a steeple-house, and their people are such as are scoffers, envious &amp; drunkards, thieves, whoremongers, and bastard-getters, and no bastard must enter into the kingdom of God, and they are fighters, proud, desperate, scornful, loving pleasures, lyars &amp; slanderers, malicious, suing one another at the law, oppressing one another, railing one of another; high-minded, &amp; trampling one of another; &amp; spiteful &amp; treacherous, where the life of God and Scriptures rules not; these are the waies of unrighteousness, and this is the cage of unclean birds, the professed Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:104397:3"/>of the world which holds up these outward steeplehouses, and have deceived people; and have told them that the steeplehouse was the <hi>church;</hi> but now is the day of the Lord come, wherein all things are made manifest to the children of light, and therefore all people that are here, Christ is not in the letter; nor the life is not in the letter; nor the word is not in the letter; this mediate stuff hath reigned long in the cage of unclean birds; this Babylon some have builded up, and some have thrown down; but now the eternal day is coming, and the eternal God is rising, and Babylon hath come in remembrance before him, and he begins to dash the children against the stones, that many of them are broken in pieces. Jesus Christ saith, I am the light of the world, &amp; enlightneth every one that cometh into the world; he that loves this light, shall have the light of life; but you that hate this light which Christ hath enlightned you withall, you hate Christ, and this light is your condemnation, for with this light you know your deeds to be evil; to that in all your consciences I speak, there is no Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on hath tasted so much of the love of God as this, not in all the world; therefore all love the light which Christ hath enlightned you withall, which is the light of Christ, that is the light in you which shews sin and evil; to that in all your consciences I speak, male and female, which is the light of Christ in you, which Christ the Head hath enlightned you withall, that is it in you which must open their conditions to you which was in the light, and it will bring you all into the fear of the Lord, and to avoid all the workes of darkness; for the Lord hath a mighty work to do in this Nation, that thousands of thousands shall mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifie,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:104397:3"/>and glorifie, and praise his great Name: The Lord of heaven and earth, the harmonie of the host of heaven is now appearing, and the glorie of the Lord is now appearing and shining, and the Serpent, the Dragon, which hath deceived the Nations shall be seen; the Angel is gone forth to bind him, this is the daie that he shall be put into the pit; and this is the word of the Lord And every one that hates this light which Christ hath enlightned you withall, you get the Letter for the Light, a Steeplehouse for the Church, <hi>Matthew, Mark, Luke</hi> and <hi>John,</hi> for the Gospel, and the Gospel is everlast<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and changeth not; and you put <hi>Hebrew, Greek,</hi> and <hi>La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine</hi> for the original, and the same is that original which your father <hi>Pilate</hi> had, who was against Christ, which was the ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal and the fountain.</p>
            <p>So all who love this light within, love Christ, and so <hi>Pilate</hi> and his generation which crucified Christ had that original; therefore all wait in the light which is of Christ in you, there is your Eye by which you will see all deceit, and see the Head which is Christ, the Substance, the end of the Prophets, the end of the Law, the substance of all the Scriptures: So to that in all your consciences I speak, and have cleared my con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>science, which is the light of Christ in you; and this is the light of Christ, being disobedient to it, the wrath of God a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bides upon you.</p>
            <p>That God that made the world dwells not in Temples made with hands, neither is he worshipped with hands; the mighty day of the Lord is coming, and is to be cried in all the Steeplehouses in <hi>England,</hi> to be read and cried, <hi>The God that made the world, dwells not in Temples made with hands, neither is he worshipped with the handy-work of men;</hi> and Christ Jesus saith he is <hi>the light of the world, and doth enlighten every one that cometh into the world;</hi> and you are all enlightned that hate it; and that is the light that shews you sin, and the works of darknesse, and the deeds of darknesse, and swearing, and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king Gods name in vain which Christ forbids, who saith, <hi>In all your communications let your yea be yea, and your nay nay, whatsoever is more, is evil;</hi> so you that hate this light, hate Christ, which light shall be your eternal condemnation; and
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:104397:4"/>now that is manifest which was in the Apostles, which the Scriptures was given forth from, which the Apostles went in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Synagogues and Temples, &amp; Meetings of them that had the Letter, &amp; they was persecuted &amp; haled out of the Syna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gogues &amp; Temples, the meetings of them that had the lettter, &amp; put into the stocks &amp; prisons, them was that had the spirit that gave forth the letter. Now in this our age we which have the spirit which gave forth the Scriptures, which the Apostles was in, which was moved to go into the high places, which som calls Synagogues, some Temples, some Churches, among them that have the <hi>Scriptures,</hi> but not the spirit that gave it forth, they hale us out that hath the spirit that gave forth the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, &amp; many knocked down in their meeting-places, &amp; struck down with their sticks, &amp; haled before Magistrates &amp; sent to prison, and these are them that Christ speaks of, that should hale out of the Synagogues, that did neither know the Son, nor the Father; and so they are doing now against us their works and actions in this generation, as the Jews did in the dayes of the Apostles, that had the letter and not the spirit that gave it forth, which the Jewish Christians now in the letter, are found in the steps which the Jews in the letter was, which now are against the Christians in the spirit, as they were against the Jews in spirit; now this is fulfilled in our dayes and seen, and the night of Apostacie which hath been since the dayes of the Apostles; and now the life is risen, which guided the Apostles, the spirit of God, which is it the world stands against now: Now you that think it a strange thing for those that have the spirit to go amongst them that have the letter in the high places, and hath got a house, and calls it a Church, when as the Saints Church is in God, which Church is the pillar and ground of truth, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out either spot, or wrinckle, or blemish, or any such thing; was it not the Apostles practice to go into the Synagogues and Temples to dispute with them? Was it not their customs to go to dispute with them that held forth the first Priest<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood? the Apostles that had the second priesthood? Was it not the practice of the Prophets of God to cry against their high places, to go to their high places and cry against them?
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:104397:4"/>and was not people defiled with their high places, and in them, and did not they set up the high places, and trust in them, and go there to do their service, as you do now in your high places, who pratend to do your service to God; and did not the Kings that feared God throw down the high places, and did not their Kings that did not fear God set up the high places, and did not the Prophets of God, that did fear God, cry against these Kings that set up the high places, and were not many of them struck for so doing? And is it not so now in this age as you may see in ages past; if you do but see all along in their age and generation of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets and Apostles, see what they testified against, and what they suffered for testifying against, and by whom, (and did not Christ say, that was a greater than <hi>Solomon</hi>) that the Temple should be thrown down which <hi>So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lomon</hi> had built, and one stone should not be left upon another, after he had thrown out the buyers and sellers &amp; clensed it, was not <hi>Steven</hi> stoned for crying against the Temple, and denying it, and witnessing the sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance Christ? And was not <hi>Paul</hi> hall'd out of the Temple and immedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ately the doors were shut, and was it not the first Priesthood that held up the temple, did ever any that witnessed Christ come in the flesh, hold up either Temple, or Synagogue, or first Priesthood? Answer this all ye Priests and People, that holds up Temples, and Priesthood that takes Tythes? Did ever any of the believers of Christ Jesus the substance of the Prophets, set up any high place, and idol it, and call it a Church, or a Temple, but on the contrary witnessed against high places; but said our bodies are the temples of God, &amp; God dwells in them, &amp; walks in them, and he would be their God, and they should be his people; though they might have answered and said, Did not God say he would dwell in the Temple at <hi>Jerusalem,</hi> and did not Christ come and say it should be thrown down, and the Apostles say their bodies were the temples of God: so it was a hainous thing to have the Heathens high places cryed against in their dayes, and to have the Jews high places cryed against, which they had set up which had transgressed the law of God; for the building the high places was in the transgression, and likewise it was a hainous thing to cry against the temple, that God had commanded, and to bring people off from that, and to cry against the Priesthood that holds it up, &amp; bring them to Christ the second Priesthood: so likewise now it is a hainous thing now in our dayes to cry against that you call your Church, that which the Papists set up, and filled the windows with pictures, &amp; it is that which you call your Church, the high place of Idolatry; it takes away your life, to cry against your Church, to take away your high place of Idolatry, there, and tell you, God is not worshiped in temples made with hands, but God is a spirit, and must be worshiped in spirit and truth; you rage like the Heathen, and as they did when their high places were cryed against, and rage like the Jews, which was in the letter, without the spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit that gave it forth; full of fury as they were, you are now who sees not that which the Scriptures speaks of; Did ever any of the second Priest<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood hold up Synagogue, Temple, or High place; who worshiped God in spirit and in truth, which the Devil abode not in, and such as was in the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:104397:5"/>letter out of the spirit that gave forth Scriptures, and out of the truth.</p>
            <p>This is a call out of all the High places in the world, up to God, to the light, and to turn to the light, that they may come to his day, even to the light, and to the truth, and to receive his spirit, and that they may worship him in the spirit and in the truth; and to come out, and from all Temple worship, made with hands, for they that worship there, do wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship they do not know what; God is a Spirit, and they that worship him, worship in spirit and truth, &amp; such the Father seeks to worship him; and this hour is now come, &amp; this is to go abroad in all steeple-houses in the Nation, and their high places, and through the world, that they may come to God from them, into the light of his Son, whom God bid hear, &amp; Christ saith, Learn of me who is the Way to the Father, &amp; no man com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth to the Father but by him, who is the light which every man is light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed withal, who is now come to reign, he lighteth every man thar cometh into the world, that all men through him might believe (that is the end) in him who is the light, the way, the truth, the life; but now they which have the high places the temple which they call a Church; Priests and People, they that do not believe in the light which enlighteneth every man that cometh into the world, which have the Scriptures which de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clares of it, so believing not in the light they are stumbling in the day, at noon time, the highest time of the day, the highest time of the light, and so the Jews did stumble at the light, which spake of a <hi>Messiah</hi> that was to come, a Christ was to come and believed it, and read of him every Sabbath day in their high places, Synagogues &amp; Temples, as they do that hath the letter now; but out of the light, preach a Christ which is to come, and is come, but without them; thus they preach him in their high places which the Papists set up, some calls synagogues, some calls Churches, some calls temples, so they believe a Christ is to come which have the letter, as the Jews did, but the Jews did not believe in the light which enlightened every man that cometh into the world, but they were enlightened, and the Christians doth believe in the light which doth en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lighten every man which cometh into the world, because they are en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lightened, that through him they might believe, that is the end; but they say they believe because the scripture declares it, but not in the light which Christ saith believe in, which enlighteneth every man that cometh into the world; so Christians that be in the letter believes not in the light, their belief differs nothing from the Jews that was in the transgres<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion; nor from the Devils, that believes and trembles; for they that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve not in the light, they are of him who abode nor in the truth, which is the light: But I do not say the Christians, but I say the Christians that be in the spirit believe in the light; the second Priesthood, and so read these things, and see where you are, and what you hold up, for the day is come and makes manifest, what every mans worships and holds up, Glory, glory, to the Lord God for ever that the day is come that makes manifest what every man worships, and holds up.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Simmons,</hi> at the <hi>Bull</hi> and <hi>Mouth</hi> neer <hi>Alders<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate,</hi> 1657.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>